<content>
Hello,

Welcome to the F1 rules of DeerGaming. In this tab, you can find several rules of DeerGaming. Of course, the version you find here are simplified.
Full rules such as 'Faction Rules', 'Vehicle Consultation Team Rules' and rules regarding legal and illegal roleplay can be found on the forums.

"The Golden Rule"

First and foremost, as a member of this community, you're expected to treat people as you'd like to be treated. Unless you have some sort of desire to be treated poorly, what we actually mean is treat people with respect and be kind. Use common sense while in-game and remember that everyone is just here to have fun.

The "Golden Rule" is the that of everyone being polite to each other, showing respect, helping people who may be new to our server and in general being a good community member. We hope you take this rule as seriously as you do the rest, because you can find yourself in trouble if you don't.


_______________________________________________________________________________

BASIC SERVER RULES


1) Multiple accounts

You are not allowed to use more than one account on our MTA server and forums. Getting caught with 2 or more accounts will result in a permanent ban, with the option of a ban appeal to explain yourself on the forums. The permanent ban is done as a precaution.


2) Transferring assets

Transferring assets is strictly limited to premium users. If you wish to transfer money, vehicles, property or other assets, purchasing the perk with gamecoins is mandatory.

Getting caught transferring assets without the perk will result in a complete reset of your characters. This includes dropping money on one character and picking it up with another, but also doing it via faction menu or other players.


3) Server Advertising

Sending other players links or discussing other servers, communities or groups in the manner of advertising is strictly prohibited. We expect all players to keep their opinions about said matter to themselves, as we hope members from other corners of the gaming world would do the same for us.


4) Breaking rules

Under no circumstance are you allowed to break rules because someone else did. If you witness somebody breaking any rules, report them to an administrator immediately. Do not start breaking the rules yourself else you'll face punishment.


5) Private messaging

Private messaging players is allowed, if no in character information is being exchanged, as that is in conflict with the metagaming rules. Also private messaging on duty administrators is limited to anything unrelated to their job as administrator. They should not be contacted in regards to reports, issues or anything similar, directly. You may PM the staff member once he has accepted your report.


6) Bugs

You are not allowed to abuse bugs, bugs are considered as actions in which are not intended, such as duplication of items/money/vehicles.
You are required to report any bugs you find using our mantis .
Failure to report bugs and instead using them for your own benefit/gain will be met with a severe punishment that may include permanent ban and a reset of your account.


7) Types of currencies

There are 2 kinds of currencies. OOC and IC ones. IC currencies include everything with money, vehicles, properties used by your character. OOC currencies includes GameCoins, real money,... used by yourself, as person. These currencies are not to be mixed. Exchanging IC currencies for OOC ones or vice-versa, is not allowed. Doing so may result in a full account reset, decided by the Upper Administration.

Selling accounts for money is also strictly forbidden and will result in full account reset. Accounts are considered private, personal and unique to one player.

Transactions with IC currencies, based on OOC deals will also be nullified and lead to a full reset of characters. It is far below our server standards.


8) Re-texturing

Re-texturing an interior is made possible scriptwise, yet has its rules in order to maintain a certain level of decency.

Erotically tinted pictures may only be used in personal spaces. Showing these in an interior which is accessible for a large amount of player is not allowed. Racism, discrimination, politically/socially unacceptable pictures and similar are strictly forbidden.

We play in a multi-etnic and multi-age server, keep in mind that not everyone has the same ideas as you do.


9) Inactivity

During inactivity, your interiors may be force-sold. If the interior is force-sold with this reason, it is not refundable.

However, your interior may also be force-sold wen it is owned by a character-killed character, killed at least 7 days prior to the force-sell.

Vehicles will never be force-sold, unless it has been parked in a force-sold interior and you have been inactive for 14 days. When being impounded you also have 14 days to release your vehicle, else the towing faction may claim your vehicle and sell it to another player.

Money, inventory assets and characters will never be removed, unless your abuse has been noted and a full character reset is needed.

Faction positions are not guaranteed when going inactive, this is all depending on the faction policy. This is to be incorporated in the faction OOC rules and cannot be forced upon by an administrator.


10) TeamSpeak

TeamSpeak is an official chat channel use and managed by DeerGaming. Rules regarding advertising, spamming, harassing and common sense apply in there as well.

You may also not possess a sidechannel within our system. SIdechannels are limited to players with certain access. Faction leaders, administrators, etc may request these.

TeamSpeak can also not be used as an in-character chat. It will be considered metagaming and punished accordingly.


11) Impersonations

Impersonating another player, by using a similar account name, creating a certain level of confusion is not allowed. Account names are considered personal and must remain so.

Portraying yourself as a staff member is strictly forbidden and may lead to harsh punishments. DeerGaming chooses its staff members carefully and wishes to keep doing so. Impersonation can hurt our image as a server.


_______________________________________________________________________________

BASIC ROLEPLAY RULES


1) Metagaming
Metagaming is when someone uses out of character (OOC) information for in character (IC) purposes. If you attempt to incite metagaming, then you're also breaking rules.

Out of character information can range from things you got to know via Skype chats, nametags above characters, /b, /f,...


2) Powergaming
Powergaming is where you force actions upon someone, don't allow the other player to retaliate, use items which you haven't physically obtained -- or acting completely superhuman. Another additional way is one in which not a lot of people realise, but it's the act of twisting role-play and situations to benefit your character without taking into account any negativity in which you should be role-playing.

Factors such as age, wounds, emotionally stressful situations, etc. are all factors which decide whether or not you are powergaming.

Using vehicles such as lowriders, exotics,... for off-road or on other unfit surfaces will be considered powergaming if the vehicle has not been modified accordingly. Doing such action may have consequences IC'ly (ending up with your car broken) and OOC'ly.


3) Deathmatching
- 3.1) Deathmatching is the act of killing another persons character without sufficient reason. The same goes for smashing your left mouse button repeatedly without any prior role-play, or agreement.

- 3.2) Revenge killing also falls under this rule. This is where you return to the scene in which you were killed and continue role-playing. If you are player-killed, that means that your memory of said recent events is wiped. You may not return to the same location, and/or people to continue that particular role-play.


4) Bunnyhopping
Bunnyhopping is the act of smashing your shift key (or jump key) in order to transport yourself quicker (whilst on foot of course). It is very unrealistic as it is considered misuse San Andreas' poor physics.


5) AFK'ing
Leaving your computer/keyboard unattended whilst you have a character logged in to the server is prohibited. Please make use of the F10 feature and return yourself to the character selection screen. It is recommended that if you wish to AFK, please do so in an environment that isn't public, i.e. your home or a quiet area of the server. Doing this in a public place may obstruct other players roleplay.

Measures are in place to seek out those that are inactive for ten minutes or longer. Abusing the script to avoid being detected is a permanent ban.


6) Always roleplay
This is a role-play server and no-one is allowed to force a situation to go out of character unless it's an administrator. If you attempt to slow role-play down (especially during a robbery) then you're also breaking this rule. "Role-play now, report later." is a great saying -- ensure that you continue to role-play even if you disagree with what's going on until an administrator arrives.


7) OOC communication during roleplay
Sometimes a player may attempt to communicate with you during roleplay. This may be because he wants to ask you a question in regards to the roleplay, or perhaps do not like the way things are turning out. When this happens, you are allowed to ignore these players and you are not required to reply.

However, we encourage players helping each other out when questions raise about the gameplay.


8) Extreme or disgusting roleplay
Every single party involved must OOCly agree to the below sorts of role-play taking place;

- Rape
- Cannibalism
- Pedophilia
- Bestiality
- Necrophilia
- Sexual harassment

Do bare in mind that although all parties may have agreed to said role-play, you must not conduct this role-play in public. 'Public' is to be defined as whereby other members of the community can see said disgusting role-play occur, and they did not OOCly agree to witness the role-play. If you have people OOCly agree to witnessing the role-play, then fine -- but it must not occur in a public place where people are continuously visiting.

You may also stop at any point during the role-play if you wish not to continue. This rule is set in place out of respect for the players and other people who may have trouble with it.


9) Inventory
All items, money and weapons in your inventory must be roleplayed on your characters person. If you don't want to be caught with an illegal item, we have features and scripts in place for you to utilize wherein you can move such things.

If you had an item stored elsewhere, it shouldn't be on you, which will lead to a powergaming situation.


10) Stunting
Using map objects as ramps is not allowed. You must refrain from stunting with your vehicle otherwise you'll be met with a punishment, based on the severity of the act.


11) Character and Player Kills
Shootouts, brawls, general kills, etcetera are player-kills (PK's).

Situations where CK's apply include, but are not limited to:
- Organized robberies (for the ones performing it);
- Showing disregard for your life (for criminals, civilians and LEO's);
- Failure to handle vehicles well, in aviation roleplay or with heavily upgraded vehicles;
- Roleplaying death, at any time;
- Provoking factions, both legal and illegal;
- OOC/Trolling behavior which has caused IC trouble or immersion of other players;
- ...

- In the case of police shoot outs, CKs may apply if the ratio exceeds 3 LEOs for each shooter. (3:1)

In order to PK or CK a player, they must first be killed script wise.

Being CK'd also includes the limitation of not being able to rejoin the same faction with alternative character in the first 7 days, following to the CK.


12) Immersion
As it has become clear to you, this is a roleplay server. It is for that reason that we try to maintain a certain level of immersion for those who wish to play as a certain type of person. Making sure they are in a realistic environment can only help to achieve that.

In order to allow the immersion as much as possible, unrealistic scenarios and situations are not allowed. Permanently parking your exotic sportscar or simply any vehicle which is considered pricy, is not allowed. If an administrator sees one of these vehicles, he will check if you are online. If you are, he will request you to remove the vehicle from the area. If you are not online, the vehicle will be respawned. If it respawns at that location, it will be moved to another location (admin lounge) or removed (/delveh) and the handling administrator will leave a note with the vehicle ID, which you can reclaim (/restoreveh) via a report to a full administrator.


_______________________________________________________________________________

</content>
